Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Jews Against the Occupation Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009-Jan 10, 2010; Jews Against the Occupation.
  Jews Against the Occupation is a progressive, secular New York City-base group that advocates peace through justice in Palestine and Israel. The organization opposes the Israeli occupation in Palestine.
  Arab-Israeli conflict |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Jewish radicals |z United States.; Jews |z United States |x Political activity.
- Jews for Racial & Economic Justice (U.S.) Archived Website, Sep 29, 2007- ongoing; Jews for Racial & Economic Justice (U.S.)
  Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) is a membership-based organization founded in 1990 that engages Jews to pursue and win racial and economic justice including via systemic changes, in partnership with people of color, low-income, and immigrant communities in New York City.
  Jews |z New York (State) |z New York |x Political activity.; Jews |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social conditions.
- Jews Say No: Not In Our Name! Archived Website, Jun 20, 2011- ongoing; Jews Say No: Not In Our Name
  JEWS SAY NO! was founded in New York City in December 2008/January 2009 to protest against the blockade of Gaza and against Israel’s oppression of the Palestinian people. The organization holds demonstrations, performs street theater, supports and sponsors protest actions, and hosts discussions, supporting justice for the Palestinian people.
  Arab-Israeli conflict |y 1993 |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Arab-Israeli conflict |y 1993 |x Peace.; Jews |z United States |x Attitudes toward Israel.
- Jubilee USA Archived Website, Oct 2, 2007 - ongoing; Jubilee USA.
  Jubilee USA Network, founded in 2000, Network is an alliance of more than 80 religious denominations and faith communities, human rights, environmental, labor, and community groups working for the definitive cancellation of debt owed by countries with high levels of human need, the cancellation of odious debt, and an end to the imposition of economic policies as a condition for debt relief. The website publishes news, resources, and a blog entitled, “Blog the Debt.” Jubilee USA promotes its mission through public education, grassroots organizing, media outreach, policy analysis and advocacy.
  Anti-globalization movement.; Debts, External |z Developing countries.
- J-Street Archived Website, Jun 5, 2011- ongoing; J Street (Organization)
  J Street established in 2008, is a Washington DC-based Jewish American political action organization that supports a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, which they believe is essential to the survival of Israel as the national home of the Jewish people. J Street advocates active American diplomatic leadership to achieve a two-state solution and a broader regional, comprehensive peace and to ensure a broad debate on Israel and the Middle East, particularly within the Jewish community. The J Street family of organizations is comprised of J Street, JStreetPAC, and the J Street Education Fund.
  Arab-Israeli conflict |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Jews |x Political activity |z United States.
- J-Street U Archived Website, Mar 17, 2012- ongoing; J Street (Organization)
  J Street U is the student run network that works on campuses through North America to promote peace, social justice, and a two state solution in Israel and Palestine. The website contains chapter contacts and listings, information on workshops and other education and advocacy, resources, and news. The organization is affiliated with J Street.
  Arab-Israeli conflict |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Student movements |z United States.
- Justice Policy Institute Archived Website, Mar 10, 2012- ongoing; Justice Policy
  The Justice Policy Institute is a national nonprofit organization that works to reduce the use of incarceration and the justice system and promote policies that improve the well-being of all people and communities. Their research and analyses identify programs and policies and use it to inform the media, policymakers and advocates. They also provide training and technical assistance supports to people working for justice reform. The website contains a blog, news updates, and research bulletins.
  Imprisonmente |z United States.
- Justseeds Archived Website, May 21, 2011- ongoing; Justseeds Artists’ Cooperative
  Justseeds Artists’ Cooperative is a decentralized network of 26 artists committed to making print and design work that reflects a radical social, environmental, and political stance, and that in concert with collective action, real change can be achieved. Justseeds produces collective portfolios, contribute graphics to struggles for justice, art installations, and other activities. The website features the art by the artists in the collective.
  Graphic art.; Graphic artists.
- KPFA 94.1 FM Berkeley Archived Website, Aug 24, 2009- ongoing; KPFA (Radio station: Berkeley, Calif.)
  Founded in 1949 by Lewis Hill, a pacifist, poet, and journalist, KPFA was the first of the Pacifica network of community supported radio stations in the USA. KPFA broadcasts on 94.1 FM and KPFB 89.3 FM, Berkeley, and KFCF 88.1 FM, Fresno, California. KPFA includes original and local programming; they also broadcast live music, demonstrations, cultural events and other events. KPFA broadcasts Democracy Now! and other Pacifica Radio programming as well. KPFA also works to promote freedom of the press, cultural diversity, serve as a forum for various viewpoints, and maintain an independent funding base.
- KPFK 90.7 FM Archived Website, Jul 16, 2011- ongoing; KPFK (Radio station: Los Angeles, Calif.)
  KPFK 90.7 FM is a Pacfica Foundation radio station, located in Los Angeles, California.
- KPFT 90.1 FM Archived Website, Jul 17, 2011- ongoing; KPFT-FM (Radio station: Houston, Tex.)
  KPFT 90.1 FM is a Pacfica Foundation radio station, located in Los Angeles, California. KPFT was founded by journalist Larry Lee in 1970 in Houston.
- Labor Party (U.S.) Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007 - ongoing; Labor Party (U.S.)
  The South Carolina Labor Party, founded in June 1996 at a convention of 1,400 delegates from hundreds of local and international unions as well as individual activists. The Labor Party platform includes issues such as healthcare and the rights to organize, bargain, and strike. They attempt to run candidates in South Carolina.
  Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.; Third parties (United States politics)
- Labor Upfront Newsletter Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010-Mar 23, 2013; Communist Party of the United States of America. Labor Commission.
  Labor Upfront Newsletter is the online publication of the Labor Commission of the Communist Party, USA, which directs the Party's work in the labor movement.
  Commission.; Communism |z United States.; Labor unions and communism |z United States.
- La Lutta New Media Collective Archived Website, May 7, 2008- Jul 17, 2013; La Lutta New Media Collective.
  La Lutta New Media Collective (NMC), founded in 1997, is a community-based organization promoting a greater level of social awareness through new media. La Lutta offers new media technical assistance to non-profit, community and grassroots groups, and is also a production house for these groups as well as students, artists, and other individuals.
  Alternative mass media |z United States.; Community organization |z United States.
- Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy Archived Website, Mar 2, 2012- ongoing; Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy
  Founded in 1981, the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy is a non-profit educational association of lawyers and legal scholars that engages in research and advocacy in support of the global elimination of nuclear weapons and a more just and peaceful world through respect for domestic and international law. LCNP serves as the UN office of IALANA, the International Association of Lawyers Against Nuclear Arms. LCNP provides legal and policy analysis to national and international policymakers, civil society, and media; publishes books and papers; advocates in UN and Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty settings, and in Washington, DC; works in disarmament and peace networks and campaigns; and provides legal assistance to individuals and organizations working for disarmament and peace. The website contains news, publications, and links to affiliated organizations.
  Lawyers |x Political activity.; Nuclear disarmament.
- League for Industrial Democracy Archived Website, Dec 6, 2012; League for Industrial Democracy.
  This website is the site for the contemporary League for Industrial Democracy, descended from the League founded in 1905 by Upton Sinclair, Jack London, Clarence Darrow, Norman Thomas and other writers and civic leaders. The League for Industrial Democracy was an American educational organization dedicated to increasing democracy in economic, political, and cultural life. The contemporary members of the League work for full racial equality, the abolition of poverty, the strengthening of trade unions and cooperatives, the expansion of civil liberties, the extension of public ownership and democratic economic planning, and the realignment of political organizations with a view toward making them more responsive to the will of the people. The website contains a blog and a forum.
  Labor |z United States.; Power resources |z United States.; Right and left (Political science); Socialism |z United States.; Unemployed |z United States..; Unemployed.
- League for the Revolutionary Party - Communist Organization for the Fourth International Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009- ongoing; League for the Revolutionary Party.
  The League for the Revolutionary Party (LRP), based in the United States, is dedicated to the restoration of authentic Marxism and the political independence of the working class with an effort to recreate the Fourth International. They are affiliated with the Communist Organization for the Fourth International (COFI). They publish the political and theoretical magazine Proletarian Revolution. The LRP upholds the method of permanent revolution. The LRP aims to resurrect the method of Trotsky’s Transitional Program. The website contains analysis on current events, theory, and translations of Marxist writers.
  Fourth International.; Trotskyism |z United States.
- League of Revolutionaries for a New America Archived Website, May 19, 2011-ongoing; League of Revolutionaries for a New America
  The League of Revolutionaries for a New America, founded in 1993, is an organization of revolutionaries that advocate for an end the injustices of capitalism through the education of communism. Rally, Comrades! is the political paper of the League of Revolutionaries for a New America. Rally, Comrades! examines and analyzes the problems of the revolutionary movement, and draws political conclusions for the tasks of revolutionaries at each stage of the revolutionary process. The website contains articles on technology, the economy, politics, the revolution, communism, the corporate state, and other movements.
  Socialism |z United States.
- League of Women Voters Archived Website, Feb 18, 2012- ongoing; League of Women Voters
  The League of Women Voters, founded in 1920, is a nonpartisan political organization, encourages informed and active participation in government, works to increase understanding of major public policy issues, and influences public policy through education and advocacy. The league works to register and educate voters and improving elections and government. The website has a blog and a news outlet.
- Left Business Observer Archived Website, Apr 26, 2012- ongoing; Left Business Observer
  Left Business Observer (LBO), founded in 1986 by Doug Henwood, is an eight page monthly newsletter on economics and politics in the U.S. and the world. The website contains back issues from 1990, supplemental material, mailing list, and Henwood’s radio archives and books.
  Political economy
- Left Eye On Books Archived Website, May 12, 2012- Feb 11, 2014; Left Eye on Books
  Left Eye on Books is an online magazine dedicated to progressive book news and reviews to help activists, writers, academics, and community workers become more aware of the diversity of literature. They highlight books published by mainstream and small presses, encourage and foster debate about left scholarship, and consider fiction from a left perspective. They are publication of Conducive Media. The website contains a book clubs, news blog, author interviews, book industry news, and reviews.
  Electronic journals.; Publishers and publishing
- Left Forum Archived Website, May 7, 2010 - ongoing; Left Forum
  The Left Forum is an annual conference (in the spring), and is the successor to the Socialist Scholars Conference (SSC), established in 1981. Left Forum seeks to link the critique of neo-liberalism to anti-capitalism, and to foster radical alternatives to the established order. The conference is held at Pace University in New York City, and has over 3,000 participants, over 300 panels, and 1000 speakers, related to a chosen theme. The website contains information on conferences since 2007.
  Radicalism--United States--Congresses
- LeftShift.org Archived Website, Apr 20, 2009-Apr 12, 2013; LeftShift.org
  LeftShift.org was formed in June 2005 with the goal of showing solidarity with revolutionary Cuba against the ever-present imperialist threats from Washington, DC and Miami. Left Shift also tries to educate the US public about Cuba and its revolution, the nature of the threats against it, and opportunities for our visitors (audience) to get involved in the solidarity movement. While the current focus is Cuba, LeftShift.org stands in solidarity with all people under the gun of U.S. and U.S.-backed imperialism–from Afghanistan to Haiti to Iraq to Palestine to Venezuela–as well as communities under attack within the borders of the U.S.
  Anti-imperialist movements |z United States.; Cuba.
- Legal Services for Prisoners With Children Archived Website, Dec 5, 2012- ongoing; Legal Services for Prisoners with Children
  Legal Services for Prisoners with Children, founded in 1978, challenges the expansion of the prison industrial complex and advocates for the civil rights and empowerment of incarcerated parents, children, family members and people at risk for incarceration through responding to requests for information, trainings, technical assistance, litigation, community activism and the development of more advocates. The website contains news updates, events listings, and a publications page that includes manuals and pamphlets.
  Children of prisoners |z United States.; Prison-industrial complex |z United States.
- Leon Trotsky Internet Archive Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008-ongoing; Trotsky Internet Archive.
  The Leon Trotsky Internet Archive contains Trotsky's writings, biographical information, photographs, and other documents.
- Lesbian Herstory Archives Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011- ongoing; Lesbian Herstory Archive
  The Lesbian Herstory Archives is an archival collection of materials by and about lesbians and their communities. The Lesbian Herstory Archives exists to gather and preserve records of Lesbian lives and activities so that future generations will have ready access to materials relevant to their lives. The archive was founded in 1975, by Joan Nestle and Deborah Edel. The website lists the collections, publishes newsletters, and information about exhibits. The website also has information on how to donate to the archive.
  Feminism |x Archival resources.
- Liberty Tree Foundation Archived Website, Apr 27, 2012- ongoing; Liberty Tree Foundation
  The Liberty Tree Foundation for the Democratic Revolution is a nonprofit organization that builds strategic pro-democracy campaigns. They focus on corporations and democracy; democratic culture and federalism; democratizing defense, education, and elections; and economic, gender, global, law, local, and media democracy. The website contains news, action alerts, and event listings. The website also contains their now defunct journal.
  Democracy |z United States.; Endowments.
- Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal Archived Website, Jul 2, 2011- ongoing; Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal
  Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal is an academic journal for the Left in the post-Cold War era. The journal aims to foster discussion and dialogue between Marxists and socialists from different political traditions. It seeks to bring together those in the international left who are opposed to neoliberal economic and social policies, and reject the bureaucratic model of "socialism" that arose in the Soviet Union, Eastern Europe and China. The publishers promote a socialism that's green, feminist and anti-racism. The website contains articles, past issues of the publication, and news listings.
  Socialism |v Periodicals.
- Living Liberally Archived Website, Dec 24, 2008 - ongoing; Living Liberally.
  Living Liberally, founded in 2003 by David Alpert and Justin Krebs, provides an entrance into progressive involvement, using social interaction to promote political action. Living Liberally is built upon networks of local gatherings. These projects include: Drinking Liberally, a national network of social clubs; Laughing Liberally, a political comedy project; Screening Liberally, a politically-conscious film series; and Reading Liberally, a book tour of progressive authors.
- Lubitz TrotskyanaNet Archived Website, Aug 26, 2009- ongoing; Lubitz, Wolfgang.
  The material presented on Lubitz TrotskyanaNet, launched in 2004, was written, compiled and edited by Wolfgang and Petra Lubitzand contains chiefly bio-bibliographical information, research tools, essays and miscellanies, related to Leon Trotsky, Trotskyism and Trotskyists. Contents include: alphabetical lists of names and pseudonyms of more or less renowned Trotskyists and ex-Trotskyists; biographical sketches or notes and selective bibliographies about a number of known Trotskyists, photograph galleries, and a bibliography of texts written by and about Leon Trotsky.
  Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940.; Trotskyism |x History.; Trotskyists.
- MADRE Archived Website, Oct 10, 2007 - ongoing; Madre (Organization)
  Founded in 1983, MADRE is an international women’s human rights organization that works in partnership with community-based women's organizations worldwide to address issues of health and reproductive rights, economic development, environmental and economic justice, education, peace, violence against women, and other human rights. They provide resources and training to enable their sister organizations to meet these goals by addressing immediate needs in their communities and developing long-term solutions to the crises they face. The websites lists news, current campaigns, and resources.
- Make The Road New York Archived Website, Mar 9, 2012 - ongoing; Make the Road (New York)
  Make the Road New York, founded in 2007 through the merger of Make the Road by Walking and the Latin American Integration Center, is a community organization in Staten Island, Brooklyn, and Queens. The organization works by expanding civil rights and civic engagement; promoting health; improving housing and fostering environmental justice; and promoting access and opportunity in education through community and electoral organizing, strategic policy advocacy, leadership development, youth and adult education, and high quality legal and support services. The website contains campaigns and news.
  Housing.
- Make Wall Street Pay Archived Website, Oct 14, 2011-Oct 13, 2013; National People's Action
  Make Wall Street Pay is a campaign supported by National People Action. The campaign gives Americans the means to air grievances toward corporate banks and calls for banks to pay their fair share. The website contains "bills" sent by users posted to the website addressed to the banks.
  Distributive justice.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Malcolm X Grassroots Movement (MXGM) Archived Website, Jul 16, 2012- ongoing; Malcolm X Grassroots Movement
  The Malcolm X Grassroots Movement is an organization of Afrikans in America/New Afrikans whose mission is to defend the human rights of their people and promote self-determination in their community. The website contains a blog, information on political prisoners, and events and chapter listings.
- Maoist Internationalist Movement (MIM) Archived Website, Jul 23, 2010- ongoing; Maoist Internationalist Movement
  This is an archive of the former website of the Maoist Internationalist Movement, which was run by the now defunct Maoist Internationalist Party - Amerika. The MIM now consists of many independent cells, many of which have their own indendendent organs both online and off. MIM(Prisons) serves these documents as a service to and reference for the anti-imperialist movement worldwide. Also archived herein is a collection of revolutionary art hosted by MIM.
  Maoism |z United States.; Maoism.
- March on Wall Street South Archived Website, Jun 12, 2013; March on Wall Street South
  March on Wall Street South was a demonstration and march, affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement, during the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on September 2, 2012 in Charlotte, North Carolina. The march was meant to use backdrop of the DNC to raise awareness of their platform, which included economic justice, immigrant justice, and funds for education, healthcare, housing and other social programs. The website contains a blog with posting about news and reasoning behind the march, a schedule of events, and protest resources.
  Democratic National Convention (2012: Charlotte, N.C.); Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Margert Community Corporation Archived Website, Mar 16, 2012 - ongoing; Margert Community Corporation
  Margert Community Corporation is a nonprofit, community-based organization and is a New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) approved housing counseling agency that has been providing neighborhood preservation services, housing assistance, and housing counseling to low-income tenants and homeowners, the elderly, and persons with disabilities since 1980. Their primary service area is Far Rockaway, Queens. The website contains a calendar, photos, news, and housing counseling.
- Marxism Leninism Today Archived Website, Nov 2, 2010- ongoing; Marxism-Leninism Today: The Electronic Journal of Marxist Leninist Thought
  Marxism-Leninism Today is an electronic journal containing articles and commentaries on the theory and practice of Marxism-Leninism; contemporary dialectical and historical materialism. Its goal is to be a resource where Marxist-Leninists can discuss and apply their science to all fields of study. It contains articles that are of particular interest to Marxist scholars, both Communist and non-Communist. Topics include philosophy, religion, African American history, labor history, trade union strategy, Marxist historiography, book reviews, and other articles. The website contains articles which can be browsed by topic.
  Communism |v Periodicals.; Marxism |z United States |v Periodicals.
- Marxist Education Press Publications Archived Website, May 1, 2012-Nov 1, 2012; Marxist Education Press
  Marxist Education Press (MEP) was a publishing house, publishing academic books and a quarterly journal, Nature, Society, and Thought. The website contains a book catalog, journal articles, and book descriptions. MEP is no longer active.
  Communism.; Publishers and publishing.
- Marxist-Humanist Initiative Archived Website, Jan 8, 2010- ongoing; Marxist-Humanist Initiative